# **Georgios Kormpakis**

COMPUTER ENGINEER - SOFTWARE ENGINEER/DEVELOPER

——————————————————————————————————————
Address: Kleisouras 41, Petroupoli, Athens, 13231
Email: kormpakisgeorgios@gmail.com
Telephone: (+30) 6989126885
GitHub: kormpakis
LinkedIn: Giorgos Kormpakis
Personal Statement
Hello! My name is Georgios Kormpakis and I am a passionate Software Engineer-Developer. In my short career so far, I have mostly worked in the Front End, which is, as I found out, something that I love.
I like new challenges, I strive for perfection, I am a fan of minimalism and I love being

Work history

part of a team, of something "bigger than me". I am an active person, pleasant,

## **Software Engineer/Developer - Junior Researcher**

**EPU of the Decision Support Systems Laboratory, School of Electrical and Computer Engineering, NTUA** 

October 2020 - Now

hardworking and ambitious.

EPU-NTUA is a multidisciplinary scientific unit which carries out research and development activities providing management and decision support services on a wide range of complex business, societal and technical problems.

EPU-NTUA collaborates regularly in R&D and technical assistance projects with several major Greek, European and international organisations. It is involved in major EU programmes as well as in national programmes funded by Greek Ministries (National Economy, Industry, Energy and Technology, Environment and Urban Planning), Energy Organisations (electricity, oil, and gas sectors), regional and national authorities, and other public and private organisations.

During this period, I have participated in a number of interesting research projects. My responsibilities have been various. I participated in both the development and partially in the decision-making of the aforementioned projects and I also contributed to several deliverables.

Working in EPU-NTUA, I have made usage of several technologies, including **React.js**, **Django** and **Drupal**, as well as numerous libraries with several usages (e.g., **amCharts** for visualizations, **MaterialUI** as a front-end framework, etc).

## **Software Engineer-Developer**

#### **Synelixis Solutions**

November 2019 - September 2020

I joined Synelixis Solutions right after completing my military service, as a Junior Software Engineer-Developer. Synelixis Solutions is a respectful, greek company, which has its own products and also participates in research projects, mostly funded by the European Union.

During these months, I have been working mostly in four projects, mainly in the Front End. I have worked in **Vue.js** and **React**, using also **Next.js** in order to achieve server-side rendering in the last project. I have also used WordPress in my current job.

During this period, I have been trained to use these tools and frameworks and I have also worked efficiently under extreme pressure, when a big project had to be delivered in a very small amount of time. This project was delivered to the Greek government, and it was a big challenge, not only programmatically, but also as a test of how efficiently and quickly all the colleagues could cooperate. I also had the opportunity to plan, organize and run a promotional campaignfor my company's new product, a social media app.

#### **Editor in Chief**

#### RockRooster.gr

2014 - 2019

I have been the founder, designer, chief editor and contact manager of the Greek website RockRooster.gr, one of the most popular websites about music and cinema in the country. During these years, I designed the website, using WordPress, and had the chance to cooperate with recognized artists and the largest festivals and venues in Greece.

#### Intern

## Bank of Greece (Patras branch)

2016-2017

Internship at the accounting department of Bank of Greece's Patras branch (6 months + 6 months after contract renewal).

# **Education & Training**

# **Computer Engineering and Informatics Department**

### **University of Patras**

2010-2018

Five-year studies equivalent to a master's degree according to the European standards (300 ECTS).

### Thesis: Web content adjustment based on users' navigation habits

**Grade:** 10/10

Short Description: My thesis involved developing an Android application and serverside software development (plugins for WordPress). It also involved the creation of an experimental Ontology, as an alternative approach to the problem of setting up recommendation systems.

#### **Further Education**

I have attended various courses about Vue.js, React.js, Next.js, Nuxt.js, Django Rest Framework, Python, etc. All the courses can be seen in my LinkedIn profile.

## **Skills**

- ≈ Front End (React, Vue.js, Next.js, Nuxt.js, WordPress, Drupal)
- ≈ Ability to work at a fast-paced environment
- ≈ Programming Languages I am familiar with: HTML, CSS, JavaScript (incl. ES6), C, C++, Java, Python, PHP, MySQL, SPARQL, OWL.

- ≈ Back End (Django)
- ≈ Team player with strong communication skills
- ≈ Strong analytical and problem solving skills
- ≈ IDEs I am familiar with: WebStorm, PyCharm, Android Studio, Visual Studio, WAMP Server, Protégé, Postman.

Foreign Languages Excellent knowledge of English (Michigan Proficiency (ECPE)).	
Interests	

Leisure time Interests: Sports (watching and playing since I was a child), music, concerts, cinema and generally anything related to cultural events.